Test 3. This is the IELTS listening test. You will hear a number of different recordings
and you will have to answer questions on what you hear. There will be time for you to read
the instructions and questions and you will have a chance to check your work. All the
recordings will be played once only. The test is in four parts. At the end of the test you
will be given 10 minutes to transfer your answers to an answer sheet. Now turn to part
1. Part 1. You will hear a man talking to the
coordinator of a photography club. First you have some time to look at questions 1 to 4.
Now listen carefully and answer questions 1 to 4.
Hello, Wayside Camera Club. Brida speaking. Oh hello, my name's Dan and I'd like to join
your club. That's great, Dan. We have an application form. Would you like to complete
it over the phone? Then you can ask any questions you might have. Oh yes, thanks. OK, so what's
your family name? It's Green, Dan Green. So can I take your email address? Yes, it's dan1068
at market.com. Thanks. And what about your home address? Well, I'm about 10 miles away
from your club in Peacetown. I live in a house there. OK, so what's the house number and
street? It's 52 Marrowfield Street. Is that M-A-R-R-O-W-F-I-E-L-D? That's right. And that's
Peacetown, you said? Uh-huh. So how did you hear about our club? Did you look on the internet?
I usually do that, but this time... well, I was talking to a relative the other day
and he suggested it. Oh, is he a member too? He belongs to another club, but he'd heard
good things about yours. OK. So what do you hope to get from joining? Well, one thing
that really interests me is the competitions that you have. I enjoy entering those. Right.
Anything else? Well, I also like to socialise with other photographers. That's great. So
what type of membership would you like? What are the options? It's £30 a year for full
membership, or £20 a year if you're an associate. I think I'll go for the full membership then.
That's a good idea because you can't vote in meetings with an associate membership.
Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions 5-10.
Now listen and answer questions 5-10.
If I could just find out a bit more about you. OK. So you said you wanted to compete.
Have you ever won any photography competitions? Not yet, but I have entered three in the past.
Oh, that's interesting. So why don't you tell me something about those? Let's start
with the first one. Well, the theme was entitled Domestic Life. I see. So it had to be something
related to the home? Yeah. I chose to take a photo of a family sitting round the dinner
table having a meal. And I didn't win, but I did get some feedback. Oh, what did the
judges say? That it was too busy as a picture. Aha. So it was the composition of the picture
that they criticised? That's right. And once they'd told me that, I could see my mistake.
So what was the theme of the second competition? Well, my university was on the coast, and
that area gets a lot of beautiful sunsets. So that was the theme. Oh, sunsets. That's
a great theme. Yes, the instructions were to capture the clouds as well. It couldn't
just be blue sky and a setting sun. Sure, because they give you all those amazing pinks
and purples. Yeah, and I thought I'd done that well, but the feedback was that I should
have waited a bit longer to get the shot. I see. So the timing wasn't right. Yes, I
took it too soon, basically. And then the third competition I entered was called Animal
Magic. Well, that's a difficult subject. I know. I had to take hundreds of shots. I'm
sure, because animals move all the time. That's what we had to show. There had to be some
movement in the scene. I got a great shot of a fox in the end, but I took it at night
and, well, I suspected that it was a bit dark, which is what I was told. Well, Dan, you seem
to be really keen and we'd be delighted to have you in our club. I'm sure we can help
with all those areas that you've outlined. Thanks, that's great.
Yeah.